So now we've looked at three basic techniques that you need to pay careful attention to the situation
因此，现在我们已经了解了您需要特别注意的三种基本技术
you're in or find what you have in common.
你在或发现你有什么共同点。
Then you need to ask interesting insightful questions or make interesting insightful comments so that
然后，您需要提出有趣的有见地的问题或发表有趣的有见地的评论，以便
the other person wants to speak with you.
对方想和你说话。
And you also need to pay careful attention to body language.
你还需要特别注意肢体语言。
Now let's actually look at some examples.
现在让我们实际看一些例子。
First the first day of class.
第一天上课。
Let's say let's imagine if I say let's say it means for example.
假设让我们想象一下，如果我说让我们说它意味着例如。
OK so let's say your first day of class you're a university student you're a freshman freshman by the
好吧，假设你第一天上课 你是一名大学生 你是一名大一新生
way.
方法。
The other three years of university if you don't know freshman and then year two is sophomore then Junior
大学的其他三年如果你不知道大一然后二年级是大二然后是大三
and Senior sure many of you already already know that.
和高级确定你们中的许多人已经知道这一点。
Let's say there's another student sitting beside me I feel nervous.
假设有另一个学生坐在我旁边，我感到很紧张。
So my first lecture in college in university what's the shared situation here.
所以我在大学的第一堂课是什么，这里的共同情况是什么。
Well everybody in this lecture hall we're all students right.
好吧，在这个报告厅里的每个人，我们都是学生，没错。
We're all students and this is probably all of our first lecture probably.
我们都是学生，这可能是我们的第一堂课。
So we have a lot in common.
所以我们有很多共同点。
We share a lot.
我们分享了很多。
Right.
正确的。
So that's great.
那太好了。
We have many things that we could talk about.
我们有很多可以谈论的事情。
Here are a couple a couple of examples.
这里有几个例子。
And these are by no means the only things that you could say but I turned to the student sitting next
这些绝不是你能说的唯一的话，但我转向坐在旁边的学生
to me.
大部头书。
I don't know this person.
我不认识这个人。
OK I'm going to try to begin a conversation.
好的，我将尝试开始对话。
How much homework do you think we're going to get on the first day.
你认为我们第一天要做多少作业。
How much homework do you think we're gonna get on the first day.
你认为我们第一天会做多少作业。
I could say going to get but I'll probably say Can I get going to get going.
我可以说要去，但我可能会说我能不能去。
Now they might just say I don't know body language.
现在他们可能会说我不懂肢体语言。
That means probably they don't want to talk to me and maybe they say I don't think that he's going to
这意味着他们可能不想和我说话，也许他们说我不认为他会
give us any homework on the first on the first lecture because what could there be homework on.
在第一堂课的第一堂课上给我们任何作业，因为可能有什么作业。
We're probably just going to go over the course the course syllabus syllabus the overview for the whole
我们可能只是要复习课程 课程大纲 教学大纲 整体概述
course.
课程。
Yeah I hope so.
是的，我希望如此。
OK.
好的。
So we've started something.
所以我们开始了一些事情。
Right.
正确的。
OK.
好的。
That's one way we could say are you a chemistry major too.
这是我们可以说你也是化学专业的一种方式。
So if we're in maybe a basic biology class maybe a basic chemistry class whatever but there are a lot
因此，如果我们上的是基础生物学课，也可能是基础化学课，但是有很多
of chemistry students here chemistry majors may right be right that again that's really messy.
化学专业的化学专业学生可能是对的，这又是真的很混乱。
C h e m i s t r y.
C em i s t r y。
OK so are you a chemistry major too.
好的，你也是化学专业的。
I'm a chemistry major.
我是化学专业的。
That's what that means.
这就是那个意思。
OK.
好的。
And it doesn't matter if I'm right or wrong if he says I know that I can say oh what Major are you on
如果他说我知道我可以说哦，你是什么少校，我是对还是错都没关系
a biology major.
生物学专业。
OK.
好的。
Now we've started something.
现在我们开始了一些事情。
So why have you decided to take this professors biology class instead of Professor Jones.
那么为什么你决定上这门教授的生物课而不是琼斯教授。
Because I heard that this professor is actually really good and kind of relaxed about exams.
因为听说这个教授其实人很好，考试也很轻松。
Yeah I heard the same thing.
是的，我听到了同样的话。
We've started a conversation.
我们开始了对话。
OK.
好的。
Are you a chemistry major.
你是化学专业的。
Yes I am.
我是。
Cool.
凉爽的。
Me too.
我也是。
All right.
好的。
Now we really have something in common.
现在我们真的有一些共同点。
Why are you studying chemistry.
W你在学化学吗？
I'm studying chemistry because someday I'd like to be a pharmacist.
我正在学习化学，因为有一天我想成为一名药剂师。
Whatever conversation.
随便聊聊。
OK.
好的。
The beginning part.
开头部分。
All we have to do is get that beginning question if it's interesting enough that person shows that they're
我们所要做的就是提出这个开始的问题，如果这个人足够有趣，表明他们是
willing to talk with us.
愿意与我们交谈。
They would like to talk with us by saying a little bit more that we can then grab on to an ad to or
他们想与我们交谈，多说一点，然后我们可以抓住广告或
if they say yeah I don't know then we can see hey they don't want to talk to me and that's just fine
如果他们说是的，我不知道，那么我们可以看到，嘿，他们不想和我说话，这很好
right.
正确的。
OK.
好的。
I heard this professor speaks really fast maybe it's before the professor even came into the lecture
我听说这位教授讲得很快，也许是在教授还没来上课之前
hall.
大厅。
I heard this professor speaks really fast.
听说这位教授讲的真快。
I hope that I'll be able to take enough notes because I don't want to fail my exams.
我希望我能做足够多的笔记，因为我不想考试不及格。
You could just say this I heard this professor speaks really fast then the other student says Actually
你可以这么说我听说这个教授说得很快然后另一个学生说其实
Actually he does speak really fast but if you look back there they're recording all of the lectures
事实上，他确实说得很快，但如果你回头看，他们正在录制所有的讲座
so you can actually download the lectures after class.
所以你实际上可以在课后下载讲座。
Wow.
哇。
That's great.
那太棒了。
So if I need to I can download it and listen again.
因此，如果我需要，我可以下载它并再次收听。
If I missed something.
如果我错过了什么。
Yeah that's awesome.
是的，这太棒了。
All right.
好的。
Once again we've started a conversation that has to be an OK question.
我们又一次开始了一场对话，这必须是一个好的问题。
It doesn't have to be an amazing question.
这不一定是一个惊人的问题。
But if you turn to that person and say How about this weather.
但是，如果你转向那个人并说这种天气怎么样。
That sounds very silly right.
这听起来很愚蠢。
It sounds stupid.
听起来很愚蠢。
It's not related to the situation.
这与情况无关。
We say Do you like movies awkward strange connected to the situation.
我们说你喜欢电影尴尬奇怪的情况。
Let's look at another.
让我们看看另一个。